Finding Aid for the Talbert Family Papers, 1872-1933
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Talbert Family Papers
1872 - 1938
Mss. B79-4
Talbert family
2 boxes (1 linear foot)
The records of personal papers of Anna Maria Talbert and family between 1881 and 1938, and legal documents of the inheritance issues between 1872 and 1927.
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Talbert Family Papers, 1872-1933 are open for research.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Please see Research Library staff for information.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Mary B. Talbert (1866-1923) was an early African American leader, graduate of Oberlin College and the University of Buffalo, co-founder of the Niagara Movement of Colored People (later to become the N.A.A.C.P.) and president of the Federated Negro Women's Clubs of the United States.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, 1923-1933, of Sarah May Talbert Keelan, concerning her musical compositions and family matters; letters, 1893-1898, to William H. Talbert, her father, concerning Grand Island property; letters, 1918, to Mrs. [Mary?] Talbert from Frederick and Archibald Grimké, concerning the Frederick Douglass home; ms. and printed musical scores by Sarah Talbert Keelan; and legal papers concerning the estates of Robert Talbert and Anna Maria Talbert.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series:
I. "In the Matter of the Probate of the Will of Anna Maria Talbert" -- Transcripts of Testimony
II. "In the Matter of the Judicial Settlement of the Accounts of Anna Maria Talbert, as Administratrix, etc., of Robert Talbert, Deceased" -- Proceedings in Surrogate's Court, Erie County
III. Miscellaneous Legal Documents
IV. Family Correspondence
V. Miscellaneous Family Materials
Container
- In the Matter of the Probate of the Will of Anna Maria Talbert -- Transcripts of Testimony, (1896-1897), I.
  Arranged by chronologically, then alphabetically by person's name
  - Index to witnesses (Box-folder 1.1)
  - James Gill, December 3, 1896 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Mary Talbert, December 4, 1896 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Joseph E. Knauber, December 4, 1896 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Mary Talbert, December 9-10, 1896 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - William H.H. Talbert, December 10, 1896 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Medford A. Farrington, December 15, 1896 (Box-folder 1.7)
  - Charles M. Pierce et al., December 15, 1896 (Box-folder 1.8)
  - Dr. Joseph T. Cook, December 24, 1896 (Box-folder 1.9)
  - Dr. Joseph T. Cook, February 23, 1897 (Box-folder 1.10)
  - William H. H. Talbert, Mary Talbert, Ada Jordan, April 12, 1897 (Box-folder 1.11)
  - Jesse E. Nash, December 3, 1897 (Box-folder 1.12)
  - John U. Wayland, December 23, 1897 (Box-folder 1.13)
  - Mame Aikerns, Mary Dawson, undated (Box-folder 1.14)
  - Henry Evans, undated (Box-folder 1.15)
  - Index to witnesses (Box-folder 1.16)
  - Della Ford, undated (Box-folder 1.17)
  - Agnes Johnson, undated (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Flora M. Lindsay, undated (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Mary Talbert, undated (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Mary Thompson, undated (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Godfrey Wende, undated (Box-folder 2.5)
- "In the Matter of the Judicial Settlement of the Accounts of Anna Maria Talbert, as Administratrix, etc., of Robert Talbert, Deceased" April 17 - July 10, 1894, II.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Proceedings in Surrogate's Court, Erie County (Box-folder 2.6)
- Miscellaneous Legal Documents, 1872-1927, III.
  - Contents (Box-folder 2.7)
    Mortgage: Peyton Harris to William G. Fargo, filed, March 13, 1872
    Bond: Anna M. Talbert, Robert Talbert and Martha C. Phillips to Erie County Savings Bank, November 11, 1882
    Certificate of Title: Anna M. Talbert to Erie County Savings Bank, November 11, 1882
    Discharge of Mortgage: Erie County Savings Bank to Anna M. Talbert, Robert Talbert et al., filed, March 6, 1888
    Power of Attorney: Anna M. Talbert, Ada Jordan, Robert P. Talbert and Walter Talbert, to William H. Talbert, February 25, 1893
    Agreement (copy): William H. H. Talbert and Emeline Coy, June 14, 1897
    Summons and Complaint (2 copies): Walter T. Talbert, Ada E. T. Jordan, and Robert P. Talbert vs. William H. Talbert, individually and as Executor of the Last Will and Testament of Anna M. Talbert, Deceased, Mary B. Talbert, Ruth Elizabeth Jordan, Anna Jane Jordan, Edith Marion Jordan, Sarah May Talbert, Emeline Coy, and Henry C. Felthousen, March 4, 1899
    Citation for Judicial Settlement: William H. H. Talbert as Executor of the Will of Anna M. Talbert, January 29, 1912
    Citation (copy): In the Matter of the Estate of Anna M. Talbert, Deceased, January 29, 1912
    Copy of Answer: In the Matter of the Estate of Anna M. Talbert, Deceased, February 6, 1912
    Last Will and Testament: Sarah Talbert Keelan, June 9, 1920
    Deed: William T. Corner and Emma Corner, his wife, Clara Isabelle Bethune, and Kate Corner to William H. H. Talbert and Mary Talbert, his wife, May 4, 1923
    Sale Contract: William T. Corner and Clara Isabelle Bethune no Mary B. Talbert, Purchaser, May 4, 1923
    Deed: Kate Corner no William H. H. Talbert and Mary B. Talbert, his wife, May 29, 1923
    Affidavit - Surrogate's Court: In the Matter of the Real Estate at and Known as 515 Michigan Avenue, March 28, 1927
    Report: Surrogate's Court, Erie County. In the Matter of the Judicial Settlement of the Accounts of Anna Maria Talbert, as Administratrix, etc., of Robert Talbert, Deceased, John G. Cloak, Referee, undated
- Family Correspondence, 1893-1933, IV.
  - Contents (Box-folder 2.8)
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Aunt) Caroline Phillips to William Talbert, San Francisco, May 17, 1893, 3 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Cousin) James R. Phillips to Cousin William [Talbert], San Francisco, July 22, 1894, 4 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, David F. Day to Anna M. Talbert, Buffalo, New York, August 1894, 2 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Aunt) Caroline Phillips to William H. Talbert, San Francisco, May 11, 1896, 4 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Cousin) James R. Phillips to (Cousin) William [ H. Talbert ], San Francisco, April 13, 1897, 3 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Cousin) James R. Phillips to (Cousin) William [ H. Talbert ], San Francisco, August 13, 1897, 4 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Cousin) [ James R. Phillips ] to (Cousin) William H. Talbert, San Francisco, February 23, 1898, (1 page, incomplete)
    Autograph Letter Signed, (Cousin) Charles R. Persons to (Cousin) William H. Talbert, San Francisco, June 19, 1898, 2 pages
    Typed Letter Signed, Francis J. Grimké to the National Association of Colored Women, Washington, D.C., July 1, 1918, 3 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, Archibald H. Grimké to Mary B. Talbert, Washington, D.C., September 24, 1918, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, J.R. Salmon to Sarah T. Keelan, Court of Chancery of New Jersey, Trenton, New Jersey, September 23, 1923, 1 page
    Certified copy: Final Decree of Divorce, Chancery Court of New Jersey, Harry S. and Sarah T. Keelan, April 20, 1923, 2 pages
    Typed Letter, (Copy): W [illiam] [H.] [Talbert] to Sarah [ H. Talbert], unpaged, October 16, 1925, 1 page
    Autograph Letter Signed, Sarah [Keelan] to [William H. Talbert], New York, N.Y., November 29, 1925, 4 pages, with enclosure
    Typed Letter, Carl Fischer Inc. to Sarah Talbert, Chicago, Illinois, April 4, 1927, 1 page
    Typed Letter, Carl Fischer Inc. to Sarah Talbert, Chicago, Illinois, April 16, 1927, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, Theodore Presser Co. to Sarah Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., June 22, 1927, 1 page
    Autograph Letter Signed, Elizabeth [Brown Talbert] to Sarah May [Talbert], Empire State Federation of Colored Women's Clubs, Brooklyn, New York, June 29, 1927, 1 page
    Autograph Letter Signed, Elizabeth [Brown Talbert] to Sarah [M. Talbert], Brooklyn, New York, July 9, 1927, 2 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, Yvette Keelan to (Mother) [Sarah M. Talbert], Buffalo, New York, July 9, 1927, 2 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, Yvette Keelan to (Mother) Sarah M. Talbert, Buffalo, New York, July 14(?), 1927, 2 pages
    Autograph Letter Signed, Elizabeth B. Talbert to Sarah [ May Talbert], Buffalo, New York, July 20, 1927, 2 pages
    Typed Letter Signed, E.C. Hartwell to Sarah Talbert, Buffalo, New York, September 8, 1927, 1 page
    Typed Letter, Theodore Presser Co. to Sarah M. Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., May 21, 1928,
    Typed Letter, Theodore Presser Co. to Sarah M. Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., July 16, 1928, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, H.L. Brown to Sarah M. Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., August 10, 1928, 1 page
    Typed Letter, Theodore Presser Co. to Sarah M. Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., September 18, 1928, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, W[illiam] H. Talbert to E. Bachert, [Buffalo, New York], Nov. 5, 1928, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, Warner W. Westervelt Jr. to Sarah M. Talbert, Hackensack, New Jersey, October 18, 1929, 1 page
    Autograph Letter Signed - Same as above.
    Typed Letter Signed, Warner W. Westervelt Jr. to Sarah M. Talbert, Hackensack, New Jersey, October 30, 1929, 1 page
    Typed Letter, Theodore Presser Co. to Sarah [M.] Talbert, Philadelphia, Pa., March 20, 1931, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, W.N. DeBerry to Sarah Talbert Keelan, Springfield, Mass., Dec. 17, 1931, 1 page
    Typed Letter Signed, J. Edward Nash to Sarah M. Talbert, Buffalo, N.Y., June 19, 1933, 1 page with enclosure
- Miscellaneous Items 1881-1938, V.
  - Contents
    Program: Ceremonies at the Presentation of the Spingarn Medal, March 22, 1931
    Alumni Quarterly, New England Conservatory of Music, January, 1938, November, 1938, February 1939
    Pistol Permit: State of New York to William H. Talbert, October 15, 1914
    Program: Mary B. Talbert Memorial Service, Michigan Avenue Baptist Church, Buffalo, New York, October 13, 1929
    Biographical Sketch of Robert Talbert, undated, 1 page
    Colored Democratic Association of Erie County, typed memo, 1 page
    Manuscript sheet music: "I Believe In You", Sarah Talbert, 1928 (2 copies)
    Printed sheet music: "I Believe In You", Sarah Talbert, 1928 (2 copies)
    Printed sheet music: "My Little Sweeties Gone", Sarah Talbert Keelan, 1920
    Printed sheet music: "Pickaninny Sandman", Sarah Talbert, 1927 (4 copies)
    Manuscript copies: "Pickaninny Sandman", Sarah Talbert, 1927 (2 copies)
    Business Card: Sarah M. Talbert, Graduate of New England Conservatory of Music
    Invitation: Dedication of the Memorial Home (Frederick Douglass) August 12, 1922 2 p.
    Diary: William H. Talbert, 1881
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Keelan, Sarah T. (Sarah May Talbert); Grimké, Frederick, 1791-1863; Grimké, Archibald Henry, 1849-1930; Buffalo History Museum
Subject Terms
Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895; African American women--New York (State)--Buffalo; Composers--New York (State)--Buffalo; Grand Island (N.Y.: Island)
Genre Terms
Deeds; Scores
Associated Material
Related Resources
Mss. A80-14, Talbert Family Papers, 1894-1930